sip-scootershop.com 2019-01-24

# Scooter Shop - Accessories and tuning | SIP-Scootershop.com

**Data Protection Declaration**

**1) Information on the Collection of Personal Data and Contact Details of the Controller**

**1.1** We are pleased that you are visiting our website and thank you for your interest. In the following, we inform you about the handling of your personal data when using our website. Personal data is all data with which you can be personally identified.

**1.2** The controller in charge for data processing on this website within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is SIP Scootershop GmbH, Marie-Curie-Str. 4, 86899 Landsberg am Lech, Deutschland, Tel.: +49 (o)8191-96999-60, Fax: +49 (o)8191-96999-70, E-Mail: info@sip-scootershop.de. The controller in charge of the processing of personal data is the natural or legal person who alone or jointly with others determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data.

**1.3** The controller has designated a data protection officer for this website. He can be reached as follows: "IITR Datenschutz GmbH, Marienplatz 2, 80331 München, Tel. (0049) 89 1891 7360"

**1.4** This website uses SSL or TLS encryption for security reasons and to protect the transmission of personal data and other confidential content (e.g. orders or inquiries to the controller). You can recognize an encrypted connection by the character string https:// and the lock symbol in your browser line.

**2) Data Collection When You Visit Our Website**

When using our website for information only, i.e. if you do not register or otherwise provide us with information, we only collect data that your browser transmits to our server (so-called "server log files"). When you visit our website, we collect the following data that is technically necessary for us to display the website to you:

  * Our visited website
  * Date and time at the moment of access
  * Amount of data sent in bytes
  * Source/reference from which you came to the page
  * Browser used
  * Operating system used
  * IP address used (if applicable: in anonymized form)

Data processing is carried out in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR on the basis of our legitimate interest in improving the stability and functionality of our website. The data will not be passed on or used in any other way. However, we reserve the right to check the server log files subsequently, if there are any concrete indications of illegal use.

**3) Cookies**

In order to make your visit to our website attractive and to enable the use of certain functions, we use so-called cookies on various pages. These are small text files that are stored on your end device. Some of the cookies we use are deleted after the end of the browser session, i.e. after closing your browser (so-called session cookies). Other cookies remain on your terminal and enable us or our partner companies (third-party cookies) to recognize your browser on your next visit (persistent cookies). If cookies are set, they collect and process specific user information such as browser and location data as well as IP address values according to individual requirements. Persistent cookies are automatically deleted after a specified period, which may vary depending on the cookie. In some cases, cookies are used to simplify the ordering process by saving settings (e.g. remembering the content of a virtual shopping basket for a later visit to the website). If personal data are also processed by individual cookies set by us, the processing is carried out in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR either for the execution of the contract or in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR to safeguard our legitimate interests in the best possible functionality of the website and a customer-friendly and effective design of the page visit.

We work together with advertising partners who help us to make our website more interesting for you. For this purpose, cookies from partner companies are also stored on your hard drive when you visit our website (third-party cookies). You will be informed individually and separately about the use of such cookies and the scope of the information collected in each case within the following sections. 

Please note that you can set your browser in such a way that you are informed about the setting of cookies and you can decide individually about their acceptance or exclude the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or generally. Each browser differs in the way it manages the cookie settings. This is described in the help menu of each browser, which explains how you can change your cookie settings. You will find these for the respective browsers under the following links:

**Internet Explorer**
     <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>
**Firefox**
     <https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/privacy/websites/#cookies>
**Chrome**
     [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en)
**Safari**
     <https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac>
**Opera**
     <http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/en/cookies.html>

Please note that the functionality of our website may be limited if cookies are not accepted.

**4) Contacting**

In the context of contacting us (e.g. via contact form or e-mail), personal data is collected. Which data is collected in the case of a contact form can be seen from the respective contact form. These data are stored and used exclusively for the purpose of responding to your request or for establishing contact and for the associated technical administration. The legal basis for processing data is our legitimate interest in responding to your request in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR. If your contact is aimed at concluding a contract, the additional legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR. Your data will be deleted after final processing of your enquiry; this is the case if it can be inferred from the circumstances that the facts in question have been finally clarified, provided that there are no legal storage obligations to the contrary.

**5) Data Processing When Opening a Customer Account and for Contract Processing**

Pursuant to Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR, personal data will continue to be collected and processed if you provide them to us for the execution of a contract or when opening a customer account. Which data is collected can be seen from the respective input forms. It is possible to delete your customer account at any time. This can be done by sending a message to the above-mentioned address of the controller. We store and use the data provided by you for contract processing. After complete processing of the contract or deletion of your customer account, your data will be blocked in consideration of tax and commercial retention periods and deleted after expiry of these periods, unless you have expressly consented to further use of your data or a legally permitted further use of data has been reserved by our site, about which we will inform you accordingly below.

**6) Commentary Function**

As a user you can subscribe to the follow-up comments. You will receive a confirmation e-mail to ensure that you are the owner of the specified e-mail address (double opt-in procedure). The legal basis for data processing in the case of subscribing to comments is Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR. You can unsubscribe from current comment subscriptions at any time with effect for the future. Please refer to the confirmation e-mail for further information on the option for unsubscribing.

**7) Use of Your Data for Direct Advertising**

If you subscribe to our e-mail newsletter, we will send you regular information about our offers. The only mandatory information for sending the newsletter is your e-mail address. The indication of additional possible data is voluntary and is used to be able to address you personally. We use the so-called double opt-in procedure for sending the newsletter. This means that we will not send you an e-mail newsletter, unless you have expressly confirmed to us that you agree to the sending of the newsletter. We will then send you a confirmation e-mail asking you to confirm that you wish to receive future newsletters by clicking on an appropriate link.

By activating the confirmation link, you give us your consent to the use of your personal data in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR. When you register for the newsletter, we store your IP address entered by the Internet Service Provider (ISP) as well as the date and time of registration so that we can trace any possible misuse of your e-mail address at a later time. The data collected by us when registering for the newsletter will be used exclusively for the purpose of advertising by means of the newsletter. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time via the link provided in the newsletter or by sending a message to the responsible person named above. After your cancellation, your e-mail address will immediately be deleted from our newsletter distribution list, unless you have expressly consented to further use of your data or we reserve the right to use data in excess thereof, which is permitted by law and about which we inform you in this declaration.

**8) Processing of Data for the Purpose of Order Handling**

**8.1** To process your order, we work together with the following service provider(s), which support us wholly or partially in the execution of concluded contracts. Certain personal data is transferred to these service providers in accordance with the following information.

The personal data collected by us will be passed on to the transport company commissioned with the delivery within the scope of contract processing, insofar as this is necessary for the delivery of the goods. We will pass on your payment data to the commissioned credit institution within the framework of payment processing, if this is necessary for payment handling. If payment service providers are used, we explicitly inform you of this below. The legal basis for the transfer of data is Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR.

**8.2** Passing on Personal Data to Shipping Service Providers

**DHL**

If delivery of goods takes place by the transport service provider DHL (Deutsche Post AG, Charles-de-Gaulle-Straße 20, 53113 Bonn), we will pass on your e-mail address to DHL in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR, prior to delivery of the goods, for the purpose of coordinating a date of delivery or of a notice about the shipment status, if you have given your express consent during the ordering process. Otherwise, only the name of the recipient and the delivery address will be passed on to DHL for the purpose of delivery in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR. The data will only be passed on if this is necessary for the delivery of the goods. In this case, prior agreement of the delivery date with DHL or transmission of status information for shipment delivery is not possible.

The consent can be revoked at any time with effect for the future either with the controller or with the transport service provider DHL.

**UPS**

If delivery of goods takes place by the transport service UPS (United Parcel Service Deutschland Inc. & Co. OHG, Görlitzer Straße 1, 41460 Neuss), we will pass on your e-mail address to UPS in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR, prior to delivery of the goods, for the purpose of coordinating a date of delivery or of a notice about the shipment status, if you have given your express consent during the ordering process. Otherwise, only the name of the recipient and the delivery address will be passed on to UPS for the purpose of delivery in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR. The data will only be passed on if this is necessary for the delivery of the goods. In this case, prior agreement of the delivery date with UPS or transmission of status information for shipment delivery is not possible.

The consent can be revoked at any time with effect for the future either with the controller or with the transport service provider UPS.

**8.3** Use of Payment Service Providers

**Paydirekt**

If you choose the payment method paydirekt, payment is made via the payment service provider paydirekt GmbH, Hamburger Allee 26-28, 60486 Frankfurt am Main. Your payment data (e.g. payment amount, details of the payee) and your confirmation that the payment data are correct will be collected, processed and transmitted to your bank by paydirekt GmbH for the execution of the paydirekt payment in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR. Such processing shall only be carried out to the extent necessary for the execution of the payment. paydirekt GmbH then will authenticate the payment using the authentication procedure stored for you with your bank. Further information about the transfer and processing of your data can be found in the paydirekt data protection declaration, which can be viewed: <https://www.paydirekt.de/agb/index.html>

**Paypal**

When paying via PayPal, credit card via PayPal, direct debit via PayPal or - if offered - "purchase on account" or "payment by instalments" via PayPal, we transmit your payment data to PayPal (Europe) S.a.r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg (hereinafter "PayPal"). The transfer takes place in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR and only insofar as this is necessary for payment processing. PayPal reserves the right to carry out credit checks for the payment methods credit card via PayPal, direct debit via PayPal or, if offered, "purchase on account" or "payment by installments" via PayPal. For this purpose, your payment data may be passed on to credit agencies on the basis of PayPal's legitimate interest in determining your solvency pursuant to Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR. PayPal uses the result of the credit assessment in relation to the statistical probability of non-payment for the purpose of deciding on the provision of the respective payment method. The credit report can contain probability values (so-called score values). If score values are included in the result of the credit report, they are based on recognized scientific, mathematical-statistical methods. The calculation of the score values includes, but is not limited to, address data. For further information on data protection law, including the credit agencies used, please refer to PayPal's data protection declaration at: <https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>.

You can object to this processing of your data at any time by sending a message to PayPal. However, PayPal may still be entitled to process your personal data if this is necessary for contractual payment processing.

**9) Contact for Requesting Customer Rating Information**

Own Evaluation Reminder (No Dispatch by a Customer Evaluation System)

We use your e-mail address as a one-off reminder for submitting an evaluation of your order regarding the evaluation system used by us, provided you have given us your express consent during or after placing your order in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR. You can revoke your consent at any time by sending a message to the controller responsible for data processing

Evaluation Reminder by Trustpilot

If you have given us your express consent during or after your order in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR, we will send your e-mail address to Trustpilot A/S, Pilestræde 58, 1112 Copenhagen K, Denmark (www.trustpilot.com), so that they can send you a reminder by e-mail. You can revoke your consent at any time by sending a message to the controller responsible for data processing or to the evaluation platform.

**10) Use of Social Media**

Facebook with Shariff Solution

Our website uses so-called social plugins ("plugins") of the social network Facebook operated by Facebook Inc, 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Facebook"). In order to increase the protection of your data when you visit our website, these buttons are not fully integrated into the page as plug-ins and only fully operational when using an HTML link. This type of integration ensures that no connection to servers of Facebook is established when a page of our website containing such buttons is called up. When you click on the button, a new browser window opens and calls up the Facebook page, where you can interact (if necessary after entering your login data) with the plugins contained there.

Facebook Inc., based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook as well as your rights and setting options for the protection of your privacy can be found in the Facebook data protection information: <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>

**11) Use of Videos**

Use of Youtube Videos

This website uses the Youtube embedding function for display and playback of videos offered by the provider Youtube, which belongs to Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google").

To this end, the extended data protection mode is used to ensure, according to provider information, that user information will only be stored once the playback function of the video is started. When the playback of embedded YouTube videos is started, the provider sets "YouTube" cookies in order to collect information about user behavior. According to indications from Youtube, the use of those cookies is intended, among other things, to record video statistics, to improve user-friendliness and to avoid improper actions. If you are logged in to Google, your information will be directly associated with your account when you click on a video. If you do not wish to be associated with your profile on YouTube, you must log out before activating the button. Google saves your data (even for users who are not logged in) as usage profiles and evaluates them. Such an evaluation takes place in particular according to Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR on the basis of the legitimate interests of Google in the insertion of personalized advertising, market research and/or demand-oriented design of its website. You have the right to object to the creation of these user profiles, whereby you must contact YouTube to exercise this right.

Regardless of whether the embedded video is played back, a connection to the Google network "double click" is established when visiting this website. This may trigger further data processing beyond our control.

Google LLC, based in the USA, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

Further information on YouTube data protection can be found in the provider's data protection statement at: www.google.com/policies/privacy/

**12) Online-Marketing**

**12.1** Google AdSense

This website uses Google AdSense, a web ad service of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google AdSense uses so-called "DoubleClick DART Cookies". These are text files are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of your use of the website. In addition, Google AdSense also uses "web beacons" (small invisible graphics) to collect information, which can be used to record, collect and evaluate simple actions such as visitor traffic on the website. The information generated by those cookies and/or web beacons (including your IP address) about your use of this website will normally be transmitted to a server of Google in the United States and will be stored there.

Google will use the information obtained in this way to analyze your usage of this website with regard to AdSense ads. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google AdSense is not merged with other Google data. The information collected by Google may be transferred to third parties, if this is prescribed by law and/or if third parties process this data by request of Google.

The described processing of data takes place according to Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR for the purpose of target-oriented advertising to the user by third parties whose advertisements are displayed on this website based on the evaluated user behavior. At the same time, such processing serves our financial interest in exploiting the economic potential of our Internet presence by displaying personalized third-party advertising content for a fee. Google LLC, based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

For more information about Google's privacy policy, please visit: <https://privacy.google.com/intl/en-GB/take-control.html?categories_activeEl=sign-in>

You can permanently deactivate cookies for advertising preferences by blocking them via a respective setting of your browser software or by downloading and installing the browser plug-in, available under the following link: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>

Please note that certain functions of this website may not or only to a limited extent be used if you have deactivated the use of cookies.

**12.2** Google AdWords Conversion Tracking

This website uses the online advertising program "Google AdWords" and the conversion tracking within the framework of Google AdWords, Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). We use the program of Google Adwords to draw attention to our attractive offers with the help of advertising materials (so-called Google Adwords) on external websites. We can determine, in relation to the advertising campaigns data, how successful the individual advertising measures is. We are interested in showing you advertisements that are of interest to you. We want to make our website more interesting for you and to achieve a fair calculation of advertising costs.

The conversion tracking cookie is set on a user’s browser, if he clicks on an AdWords ad delivered by Google. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer system. These cookies usually lose their validity after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If the user visits a certain page of this website and if the cookie has not yet expired, Google and we will be able to recognize that the user clicked on the ad and was forwarded to this page. Each Google AdWords customer gets a different cookie. Thus, cookies cannot be traced via the website of AdWords customers. The information collected by the conversion cookies is used to provide aggregate conversion statistics to AdWords customers who have opted-in for conversion tracking. Customers are informed about the total number of users who clicked on the ad and were forwarded to a conversion tracking tag page. However, they do not get any information enabling them to identify users personally. If you do not want to participate in the tracking program, you can refuse the use of this program by deactivating the Google Conversion Tracking cookie via your Internet browser through the user settings. In this case, you will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics. We use Google Adwords on the basis of our legitimate interest in targeted advertising in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR.

Google LLC, based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

For more information about Google's privacy policy, please visit: <https://privacy.google.com/intl/en-GB/take-control.html?categories_activeEl=sign-in>

You can permanently deactivate cookies for advertising preferences by blocking them via a respective setting of your browser software or by downloading and installing the browser plug-in, available under the following link: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>

Please note that certain functions of this website may not be used or only to a limited extent, if you have deactivated the use of cookies.

**13) Web Analysis Services**

Google (Universal) Analytics

\- Google Universal Analytics 

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google Analytics uses so-called cookies, which are text files stored on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookies about your use of this website (including the shortened IP address) is generally transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

This website uses Google Analytics exclusively with the extension "_anonymizeIp()", which ensures an anonymization of the IP address by shortening it and excludes a direct personal relationship. As a result of the extension, your IP address will previously be shortened by Google within member states of the European Union or in other signatory states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address will be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. In these exceptional cases, processing is carried out in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR on the basis of our legitimate interest in the statistical analysis of user behavior for optimization and marketing purposes.

On our behalf, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide us with other services relating to website and internet use. The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics is not merged with other Google data.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, we should point out that in that case you might not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You may permanently refuse Google to collect data generated by cookies regarding the use of the website (including your IP address) and to process them. You can download and install the browser plugin available under the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

As an alternative to the browser plug-in or for browsers on mobile devices, please click on the following link in order to set an opt-out cookie which disables Google Analytics to collect data on this website in the future (this opt-out cookie only functions for this browser and this domain. If you delete your cookies on this browser, you must click again on this link): Disable Google Analytics Google LLC, based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

This website also uses Google Analytics for a device-independent analysis of visitor flows, which is carried out via a user ID. You can deactivate the cross-device analysis of your usage in your customer account under "My data", "Personal data".

More information on how Google Analytics handles user data can be found in Google's privacy policy at: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

**14) Retargeting/Remarketing/ Referral Advertising**

Criteo (Criteo SA)

This website uses the technology of Criteo SA, 32 Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France ("Criteo"), to collect, store and evaluate information about the surfing behavior of website visitors in pseudonymized form using cookie text files. This is done on the basis of our legitimate interest in the insertion of personalized advertising pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Criteo analyses the navigation behavior with the help of algorithms and is subsequently able to display product recommendations in form of personalized advertising banners on other websites (so-called publishers). Under no circumstances, those data will be used to personally identify the visitor to this website. No other use or disclosure to third parties is envisaged.

If you want to object to the collection of data and the creation of pseudonymized user profiles for the future, you can obtain the following so-called opt-out cookie: Criteo Exercise (<https://www.criteo.com/fr/privacy/>)

For more information about Criteo's technology, please view Criteo's Privacy Policy at: <https://www.criteo.com/privacy/>

Facebook Custom Audience via the Pixel Process

This website uses the "Facebook Pixel" of Facebook Inc, 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Facebook"). If the user has given us his explicit consent, his behavior can be tracked after he has seen or clicked on a Facebook advertisement. This process is designed to evaluate the impact of Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes and may help to optimize future advertising efforts.

Data collected shall remain anonymous and cannot be used to draw any conclusion about the identity of the user. However, those data are stored and processed by Facebook to enable a connection to the respective user profile and to allow Facebook to use those data for its own advertising purposes in accordance with the Facebook Privacy Policy (<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>). You may allow Facebook and its partners to place ads on and outside of Facebook. A cookie may also be stored on your computer for these purposes. These processing operations only take place if express consent is given in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR.

Consent to the use of the Facebook pixel may only be given by users who are older than 13 years of age. If you are younger, please ask your legal guardian for permission. Facebook Inc., based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

If you want to disable the use of cookies on your computer, you can set your Internet browser so that cookies can no longer be stored on your computer in the future and/or cookies that have already been stored will be deleted. However, when disabling all cookies, some functions of our internet pages may no longer be able to be executed. You can also disable the use of cookies by third parties such as Facebook on the following Digital Advertising Alliance website: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>

Google AdWords Remarketing

Our website uses the functions of Google AdWords Remarketing, which enable us to advertise our website in Google search results, as well as on third-party websites. Provider is Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). To this end, Google places a cookie in the browser of your terminal device, which automatically uses a pseudonymous cookie ID on the basis of pages you visited to allow interest-based advertising. Processing is based on our legitimate interest in the optimal marketing of our website in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR.

Any additional processing will only take place if you have agreed with Google that your Google Internet and app browsing history will be linked to your Google Account and information from your Google Account will be used for personalized ads you view on the web. If you are logged in to Google while visiting our website, Google will use your data in connection with Google Analytics data to create and define target group lists for cross-device remarketing. To this end, Google temporarily links your personal data with Google Analytics data to create target groups.

You can permanently disable the setting of cookies for advertising preferences. You may download and install the browser plug-in available at the following link: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/>

Alternatively, you can contact the Digital Advertising Alliance at www.aboutads.info to find out how to set cookies and to make the relevant settings. Finally, you can set your browser so that you are informed about the setting of cookies and decide individually whether to accept them or to exclude the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or in general. If cookies are not accepted, the functionality of our website may be limited. Google LLC, based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

Further information and the data protection regulations regarding advertising and Google can be viewed at:<http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>

**15) Tools and Miscellaneous**

**15.1** Google Customer Reviews (formerly Google Certified Dealer Program)

We cooperate with Google LLC in the framework of the "Google Customer Reviews" program. The provider is Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). The program offers us the opportunity to obtain customer reviews from users of our website. After making a purchase on our website, you will be asked whether you would like to participate in a Google e-mail survey. If you give your consent pursuant to Art. 6 (1) point a GDPR, we transmit your e-mail address to Google. You will receive an email from Google Customer Reviews asking you to rate the shopping experience on our site. The feedback you provide will then be combined with our other reviews and displayed in our Google Customer Reviews logo and Merchant Center dashboard and will also be used for Google seller reviews.

You can revoke your consent at any time by sending a message to the controller responsible for data processing or to Google.

Google LLC, based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

For more information about Google's privacy practices with Google Customer Reviews, please visit <https://support.google.com/merchants/?hl=en-GB#topic=7259123>

For more information about Google Seller Ratings' privacy practices, visit this link: <https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/2375474>

**15.2** Google Maps

Our website uses Google Maps (AP’I) of Google LLC., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). Google Maps is a web service for displaying interactive (country) maps in order to display geographical information visually. Using this service will show you our location and will make it easier for you to find us. When you access the sub-pages that contain the Google Maps map, information about your use of our website (such as your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. This is regardless of whether Google provides a user account that you are logged in with or whether no user account exists. If you are logged in to Google, your information will be directly associated with your account. If you do not wish to be associated with your profile on Google, you must log out before activating the button. Google saves your data (even for users who are not logged in) as usage profiles and evaluates them. Such an evaluation takes place according to Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR on the basis of the legitimate interests of Google in the insertion of personalized advertising, market research and/or demand-oriented design of its website. You have the right to object to the creation of these user profiles. If you want to do so, you must contact Google to exercise this right.

Google LLC, based in the United States, is certified for the US-European data protection agreement "Privacy Shield", which guarantees compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

If you do not agree to the future transmission of your data to Google in the context of using Google Maps, you may completely deactivate the Google Maps web service by switching off the JavaScript application in your browser. In this case, Google Maps as well as the map display on this website cannot be used.

The Google terms of use can be found at: <https://policies.google.com/terms?hl=en>. The additional terms of use can be found at: <https://www.google.com/intl/en-US_US/help/terms_maps.html>.

You can find detailed information on data protection in connection with the use of Google Maps on Google's website ("Google Privacy Policy") at: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

**16) Rights of the Data Subject**

**16.1** The applicable data protection law grants you comprehensive rights of data subjects (rights of information and intervention) vis-à-vis the data controller with regard to the processing of your personal data, about which we inform you below :

  * Right of access by the data subject pursuant to Art. 15 GDPR
  * Right to rectification pursuant to Art. 16 GDPR
  * Right to erase (“right to be forgotten”) pursuant to Art. 17 GDPR
  * Right to restriction of processing pursuant to Art. 18 GDPR
  * Right to be informed pursuant to Art. 19 GDPR
  * Right to data portability pursuant to Art. 20 GDPR
  * Right to withdraw a given consent pursuant to Art. 7 (3) GDPR
  * Right to lodge a complaint pursuant to Art. 77 GDPR

**16.2** RIGHT TO OBJECT

IF, WITHIN THE FRAMEWORK OF A CONSIDERATION OF INTERESTS, WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA ON THE BASIS OF OUR PREDOMINANT LEGITIMATE INTEREST, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT AT ANY TIME TO OBJECT TO THIS PROCESSING WITH EFFECT FOR THE FUTURE ON THE GROUNDS THAT ARISE FROM YOUR PARTICULAR SITUATION.

IF YOU EXERCISE YOUR RIGHT TO OBJECT, WE WILL STOP PROCESSING THE DATA CONCERNED. HOWEVER, WE RESERVE THE RIGHT TO FURTHER PROCESSING IF WE CAN PROVE COMPELLING REASONS WORTHY OF PROTECTION FOR PROCESSING WHICH OUTWEIGH YOUR INTERESTS, FUNDAMENTAL RIGHTS AND FREEDOMS, OR IF THE PROCESSING SERVES TO ASSERT, EXERCISE OR DEFEND LEGAL CLAIMS.

IF WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR DIRECT MARKETING PURPOSES, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO OBJECT AT ANY TIME TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA WHICH ARE USED FOR DIRECT MARKETING PURPOSES. YOU MAY EXERCISE THE OBJECTION AS DESCRIBED ABOVE.

IF YOU EXERCISE YOUR RIGHT TO OBJECT, WE WILL STOP PROCESSING THE DATA CONCERNED FOR DIRECT ADVERTISING PURPOSES.

**17) Duration of Storage of Personal Data**

The duration of the storage of personal data is determined by the respective legal retention period (e.g. commercial and tax retention periods). After expiry of this period, the corresponding data will be routinely deleted, provided they are no longer necessary for the performance or initiation of the contract and/or there is no longer any legitimate interest on our part in the further storage.

Copyright © 2018, IT-Recht-Kanzlei · Alter Messeplatz 2 · 80339 Munich Tel: +49 (0)89 / 130 1433 - 0· Fax: +49 (0)89 / 130 1433 - 60
